A Guide to the Papers of Frank Whitney Finger, 1880-2002
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Frank Whitney Finger 1880-2002
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
12810
This collection consists of 15,000 items (50 Hollinger boxes, 21 linear feet).
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access restrictions may apply to specific student records under the terms of the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (F.E.R.P.A.).
Acquisition Information
These papers were given to the University of Virginia Library by Frank W. Finger Charlottesville, Virginia, in December, 1996 and January-February, 1997.
Biographical/Historical Information
Frank Whitney Finger was born on April 16, 1915, in Naples, New York, to the Reverend Jacob and Elizabeth Lewis Finger. He graduated from Syracuse University in 1936 (B.A.) and in 1937 (M.A.), receiving his doctorate in psychology from Brown University in 1940. Dr. Finger was a member of the University of Virginia Psychology Department from March 1942 until his retirement in 1985 and was associated with the University of Virginia Athletic Department in various capacities.
He also held appointments at Brown University (1940-1942), University of Wisconsin (1952), Yale University (1952-1954), University of Sussex, England (1975-1976), and Canterbury University, New Zealand (1981). He was active in the American Psychological Association, the American Association for the Advancement of Science, and the Virginia Psychological Association and acted as a consultant for several federal agencies and professional journals. Dr. Finger was also a member of St. Paul's Memorial Church, Charlottesville, Virginia, Phi Beta Kappa, Omicron Delta Kappa, Sigma Xi, and the Raven Society.
Scope and Content Information
This collection consists of the personal papers, ca. 1880-2002, of Frank Whitney Finger (1915-2003), professor emeritus of psychology, containing ca. 15,000 items (50 Hollinger boxes, 21 linear feet), chiefly material from his teaching and professional careers, his research, service on University of Virginia committees and Faculty Senate. Finger joined the University of Virginia faculty in 1942 and retired as full professor in 1985. Also present are files representing his students, coaching, travels in foreign countries, his athletic career and training in track and field, family papers, and his own memoirs, titled "Reminiscing."
Material generated by his work for the American Psychological Association was sent to the Association's archives at the University of Dayton.
Organization
This collection is arranged in nine series as described in the following list.
SERIES I: Correspondence Box 1
SERIES II: Academic Courses Boxes 2-4, Academic Courses, Professional Problems Boxes 4-6
SERIES III: Experiments and Research Boxes 7-17
SERIES IV: Mental Disorders Boxes 17-23
SERIES V: Organizations Boxes 23-27
SERIES VI: Foreign Travel Boxes 27-30
SERIES VII: General Files Boxes 30-42
SERIES VIII: Personal Papers Box 43, Personal Papers, Transcripts Boxes 43-44
SERIES IX: Miscellaneous and Restricted Boxes 45-50
Contents List
- I: Correspondence
  - Correspondence 1975-1985, 6 folders (Box 1)
  - Correspondence-Bremer, Mary F. 1958-1959 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence-- Frank Whitney Finger 1972-1984 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence--Guyer 1983-1985 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence-Halberg, Franz 1965-1970 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence--McLaughlin 1970 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence--Old 1970-1984 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence--Personal 1978-1979 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence--Recruitment 1953-1967 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence--Research 1978 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence-Rutherfoord, Thomas and Finger 1975-1976 (Box 1)
  - Letters 1981, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Letters from Universities 1954-1979 (Box 1)
- II: Academic Courses taught by Frank Finger and Related Materials
  - Material for Abnormal 1980-1985 (Box 2)
    Restricted
  - Abnormal Miscellaneous 1977 (Box 2)
  - Abnormal Psychology Grades 1958-1972 (Box 2)
  - Abnormal Psychology Seminar 1984 (Box 2)
  - Abnormal Psychology Syllabus 1973-1974 (Box 2)
  - Abnormal Psychology, A Syllabus in 1977-1978 (Box 2)
  - Abnormal Psychology, A Syllabus in 1982-1983 (Box 2)
  - Biochemical Seminar on Oscillators 1979 (Box 2)
  - Biology 121 1939-1940 (Box 2)
  - Book Reports 1971 (Box 2)
  - Book Reviews 1981 (Box 2)
  - Chautauqua Course 1978-1979 (Box 2)
  - Chautauqua Course Notes 1979-1980 (Box 2)
  - Chautauqua Short Course 1979-1979 (Box 2)
  - Class Notes and Questions 1982-1983 (Box 2)
  - Class Record Books 1952-1976 (Box 2)
  - Course 1990 Spr (Box 2)
  - Course, Honor 1989-1990 (Box 2)
  - Course Organization 1963-1982 (Box 2)
  - Courses, Rhythm 1979 (Box 2)
  - Current Issues in Abnormal 1982 (Box 2)
  - Evaluations 1966 (Box 3)
  - First Year Seminar 1973 (Box 3)
  - Handouts to Accompany Transparencies 1978-1980 (Box 3)
  - Introductory IR 1966 (Box 3)
  - Objectives and Evaluations 1967-1974 (Box 3)
  - Professional Problems Book Reports 1972-1973 (Box 3)
  - Psychology 341--Abnormal 1984 (Box 3)
  - Psychology 342 1980 (Box 3)
  - Psychology 342--Abnormal 1979-1985, 4 folders (Box 3)
  - Psychology 342--Evaluation 1980 (Box 3)
  - Psychology 401--Terms Papers 1984-1985, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Psychology 402--Abnormal 1983 (Box 4)
  - Psychology 402--Term Papers 1990 (Box 4)
  - Psychology 403--Exams 1990 (Box 4)
  - Psychology 403--Materials on 1990 (Box 4)
  - Psychology Class Questions 1972 (Box 4)
  - Reading Reports 1976-1977 (Box 4)
  - Seminar 1984-1985, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Seminar, LA 1978 (Box 4)
  - Student's Notes 1963-1980 (Box 4)
  - Student's Portfolio on Natural Disasters and Economic Problems 1937-1944 (Box 4)
  - Student's Scrapbook on Health Issues 1984 (Box 4)
  - Student's Scrapbook on Health Issues--Clippings 1984 (Box 4)
  - Student's Scrapbook on Psychological Problems, Crime, and Medical Discoveries 1983 (Box 4)
  - Summer School--Psychology in Contemporary Society 1983 (Box 4)
  - Comments on the Course of Professional Problems 1967 (Box 4)
  - English Department Fiasco and Econ Department 1967-1972 (Box 4)
  - Manuscript on Professional Problems 1969 (Box 4)
  - Original Professional Problems 1949 (Box 4)
  - Problems of Writing and Publication 1957-1958 (Box 5)
  - Professional Problems 1942-1969, 10 folders (Box 5)
  - Professional Problems 1968-1980, 9 folders (Box 6)
  - Professional Problem Article Follow-up 1969-1970 (Box 6)
  - Professional Problems Book Reports 1972-1973 (Box 6)
  - Professional Problems--Preparation for a Career in College Teaching 1970 (Box 6)
- III: Experiments and Research
  - Abnormal Productions 1950-1969 (Box 7)
  - Activity, 6, 12, 18, 24 Hour 1958-1960 (Box 7)
  - Activity and 23 Hour Feeding Cycles 1950 (Box 7)
  - Activity Changes Under Food Deprivation as a Function of Recording Device 1959-1960 (Box 7)
  - Activity Chapter--Correspondence 1971-1973 (Box 7)
  - Activity Chapter--Drafts 1973-1977 (Box 7)
  - Activity Restriction and Feeding Cycles 1954-1956 (Box 7)
  - Activity Restriction and Adaptation to Feeding Cycles 1955-1956 (Box 7)
  - Activity-Temperature Book II 1967 (Box 7)
  - Activity under Food Deprivation as Function of Age 1958-1959 (Box 7)
  - Aging 1981 (Box 8)
  - Air Blast Activity and Random Reinforcement 1940 (Box 8)
  - Animal Research Committee 1984-1985 (Box 8)
  - Biorhythms 1976-1981 (Box 8)
  - Carol Noll Hoskin's Research 1972-1978 (Box 8)
  - Changes in Sex Practices and Beliefs 1975-1984 (Box 8)
  - Chronobiology 1973-1976 (Box 8)
  - Circadian Pattern of Activity 1979-1985 (Box 8)
  - Circadian Rhythm 1980-1990 (Box 8)
  - Control of Behavior 1978-1984, 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Current Issues in Abnormal 1982 (Box 8)
  - Cycles of 23 Hour Food Deprivation 1955 (Box 9)
  - Cycles of 23 Hour Food Deprivation, Paper on 1955 (Box 9)
  - Data--Activity Restriction and Adaptation to Cycles 1954-1955 (Box 9)
  - Data--Noise or Quiet 1965, 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Data Sheet 1958 (Box 9)
  - Data Sheets--Reinforcement and Activity 1955 (Box 9)
  - Data Sheets--Restriction Study 1955-1956 (Box 9)
  - Data Summary--Response to Food Deprivation 1964 (Box 10)
  - Data Summary--Response to Food Deprivation of 110-120 Day Old Rats 1964 (Box 10)
  - Development of Regulations and Licensing 1966 (Box 10)
  - Direct Observation in Automatic Recording 1963 (Box 10)
  - Effect of Food Deprivation on Running Wheel Activity in Naﶥ Rats 1964-1968 (Box 10)
  - EPA--2 Measures of Activity During Deprivation and Estrous 1960 (Box 10)
  - Estrous Activity 1960 (Box 10)
  - Estrous Cycle and Activity--Wheel vs. Photo 1959 (Box 10)
  - Estrous Research 1969 (Box 10)
  - Ethics 1964-1974 (Box 10)
  - Ethics 1967-1980, 3 folders (Box 11)
  - Ethics and the Honor System 1990 (Box 11)
  - Ethics in Research 1982-1983 (Box 11)
  - Experiments 1979, photograph included (Box 11)
  - Experiments and Correspondence 1978-1986 (Box 11)
  - Finger and Reid--Photocell vs. Wheel, 72 Hour Food Deprivation 1956 (Box 11)
  - Food and Water Deprivation 1952 (Box 11)
  - Food Deprivation 1951 (Box 11)
  - Food Deprivation 1964 (Box 12)
  - General Material on Activity 1955 (Box 12)
  - Goff, M.L.R. and Finger 1966 (Box 12)
  - Goff, M.L.R. and Finger--A Diurnal Light Dark Control 1965-1966 (Box 12)
  - Graphs 1971, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Graphs and Syndicates 1971 (Box 12)
  - Issues in Contemporary Society 1983 (Box 12)
  - Lab Experiments 1971, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Lab Experiments on Mice 1922-1970, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Lab Experiments on Mice 1937-1970, 7 folders (Box 13)
  - Lab Experiments on Mice, Hamsters and Monkeys 1934-1978 (Box 14)
  - Lab Experiments on Mice and Humans 1966-1984, 2 folders (Box 14)
  - Lab Experiments on Mice and Monkeys 1933-1975 (Box 14)
  - Lab Experiments on Rats 1948-1974, 3 folders (Box 14)
  - Lab Experiments on Rodents 1955 (Box 14)
  - Lab Experiments on Rodents and Arthropods 1965-1982 (Box 14)
  - Lab Accounts 1929-1942 (Box 15)
  - Liquid Diet 1976 (Box 15)
  - Long Series of Convulsions and Activity 1950-1952 (Box 15)
  - Matthews, Spencer R., Jr. and Finger--Observations--Journal of Physiology and Behavior 1966 (Box 15)
  - Noise Raw Data 1966 (Box 15)
  - Observations with Matthews and Ferruri 1963-1964 (Box 15)
  - Oestrus Activity 1959-1966 (Box 15)
  - Photo Activity--Young Males--Food and Water Deprivation 1959 (Box 15)
  - Project Proposal Information 1959-1967 (Box 15)
  - Reid, Starling and Finger--The Rat's adjustment to 23 Hour Food Deprivation Cycles 1955 (Box 15)
  - Reid, Starling and Finger--Depravation Study Publications 1951-1957 (Box 15)
  - Reinforced Activity--72 Hour Deprivation 1956 (Box 15)
  - Reinforcement After Hour in the Wheel--22 Hour Food Deprivation 1956 (Box 16)
  - Reinforcement and Cyclic Food Deprivation--All Drafts--Correspondence 1956-1957 (Box 16)
  - Reinforcement in Wheels 1955 (Box 16)
  - Restriction and Cycles 1957 (Box 16)
  - Rhythms 1980-1982, 2 folders (Box 16)
  - Right to Life and Death--Right to Refuse Treatment, Hospice 1981-1983 (Box 16)
  - Sex Differences, Gender Roles, Homosexuality, and Aids 1983 (Box 16)
  - Social Control, Ethics, and Legislation 1966-1971 (Box 16)
  - Starvation Activity 1950 (Box 16)
  - Temperature-Activity Book I 1967 (Box 16)
  - Temperature-Activity Book 2 1970 (Box 16)
  - Tests, Group Differences, and Educational Problems 1956 (Box 17)
  - Test Questions on Psychological Diseases 1950-1961, 2 folders (Box 17)
  - 23 Hour Food Deprivation Cycles 1965 (Box 17)
  - Wheel Activity 1964 (Box 17)
  - Wheel Activity Without Prior Check Experience 1964 (Box 17)
- IV: Mental Disorders - Information Files
  - Adler Reprints 1967-1970
  - Affective Psychoses 1959-1987
  - Alcohol 1977-1988
  - Behavioral Health 1983-1984
  - Behavioral Mood Seminar, University of Sussex 1975-1976
  - Controlling Chemotherapy Side Effects 1982 (Box 18)
  - Deafness and the Development of Sign Language 1974-1978 (Box 18)
  - Deficiency and Traumatic Psychoses 1966-1983 (Box 18)
  - Devereaux Schools 1973 (Box 18)
  - Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders--I 1977 (Box 18)
  - Emotional 1957-1985 (Box 18)
  - Epilepsy 1962-1984 (Box 18)
  - ESP--Paranormal 1961-1978 (Box 18)
  - General Principles--Organic Psychoses 1968-1978, 2 folders (Box 18)
  - Insanity 1983 (Box 18)
  - Intellectual Deficit 1957-1988, 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Intervention and [?] 1980, 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Introduction to Organic Psychoses: Infections 1979-1984 (Box 19)
  - Introduction to Schizophrenia 1959-1985, 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Masters and Johnson's Sex Studies 1962-1965 (Box 20)
  - Memory 1962-1983 (Box 20)
  - Mental Illness 1962-1982 (Box 20)
  - Model Legislation 1977-1982 (Box 20)
  - Model Secondary School for the Deaf 1970 (Box 20)
  - Mood Disorders 1984 (Box 20)
  - Organic Disorders 1952-1977 (Box 20)
  - Nervous System, Muscles, Glands, Speech 1957-1984, 2 folders (Box 20)
  - Neuroses 1959-1985 (Box 20)
  - Organic Disorders 1952-1977 (Box 20)
  - Pain 1973-1982 (Box 20)
  - Perception 1958-1983, 2 folders (Box 21)
  - Personality Disorders: Sociopathy and Anti-social 1972-1985 (Box 21)
  - Psychiatry 1959-1983 (Box 21)
  - Psychological Diseases 1960-1982 (Box 21)
  - Psychophysologic Disorders 1971-1987 (Box 21)
  - Schizophrenia 1958-1964, 1986, 2 folders (Box 21)
  - Science 1974-1978 (Box 21)
  - Seizures Activity 1949 (Box 21)
  - Senile 1978-1988 (Box 22)
  - Sensory 1957-1984 (Box 22)
  - Sex 1961-1984 (Box 22)
  - Sexual Dysfunction--Transsexuals and Homosexuals 1975-1985 (Box 22)
  - Sleep and Dreaming--Percephial Deprivation 1962-1965 (Box 22)
  - Speech Disorders 1963-1969 (Box 22)
  - Suicide 1974-1984 (Box 22)
  - Therapy and [?] 1965-1978, 2 folders (Box 22)
  - Toxic Drugs 1978-1987 (Box 23)
  - Transcendental Meditation 1976 (Box 23)
  - Treatment of Alcoholics 1967-1968 (Box 23)
- V: Organizations
  - Account for the Examining Board for the Certification of Clinical Psychologists-- Virginia 1947-1950 (Box 23)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science 1960-1964, 2 folders (Box 23)
  - American Psychological Association 1976-1977 (Box 23)
  - American Psychology Association Centennial Liaison 1987-1991, 2 folders (Box 23)
  - American Psychological Association Paper 1957 (Box 23)
  - American Psychological Association Symposium 1946 (Box 23)
  - American Psychological Foundation and Association for the Advancement of Psychology 1981-1982 (Box 23)
  - American Psychologist 1964-1971 (Box 23)
  - Blues and American Psychological Association 1973 (Box 24)
  - Case of W.J. Morgan 1967-1973 (Box 24)
  - Correspondence--State Association 1967-1989 (Box 24)
  - Examination Board 1966-1973, 2 folders (Box 24)
  - Legislation 1973 (Box 24)
  - Manual of Procedures--Virginia Board of Psychologists Examiners 1970 (Box 24)
  - National Science Foundation 1962-1968, 2 folders (Box 24)
  - National Science Foundation Facilities Panel 1961-1962 (Box 24)
  - National Science Foundation Research 1958-1961 (Box 24)
  - Office of Institutional Programs Assignments and Evaluations 1961-1963 (Box 25)
  - Office of Institutional Programs Disposition Data 1961-1963 (Box 25)
  - Office of Institutional Program Financial 1961-1963 (Box 25)
  - Office of Institutional Programs General: Correspondence, Minutes, etc. 1961-1962 (Box 25)
  - Office of Institutional Programs, Instructions, etc 1961-1963 (Box 25)
  - Office of Institutional Programs Meeting 1963 (Box 25)
  - Office of Institutional Programs Travel Plans 1961-1963 (Box 25)
  - Perkins-Tyson Cases and Associated Legislation 1968 (Box 25)
  - Reorganization of Virginia Psychological Association 1982 (Box 25)
  - Revisions of Regulations 1972 (Box 25)
  - Virginia Academy 1944-1946 (Box 25)
  - Virginia Academy of Academic Psychologists and Virginia Psychological Association 1983-1989 (Box 25)
  - Virginia Academy of Clinical Psychologists 1987 (Box 25)
  - Virginia Academy of Science and Virginia Psychological Association 1957 (Box 25)
  - Virginia Academy of Science Symposium 1957 (Box 25)
  - Virginia Academy Paper 1942 (Box 25)
  - Virginia Examining Board 1963-1965 (Box 25)
  - Virginia Psychological Association 1956-1987, 4 folders (Box 26)
  - Virginia Psychological Association Board of Directors 1979-1983 (Box 26)
  - Virginia Psychological Association Policy and Planning 1986-1989 (Box 26)
  - Virginia Psychological Association Board of Scientific Affairs 1975-1986, 1 of 2 (Box 26)
  - Virginia Psychological Association Board of Scientific Affairs 1975-1986, 2 of 2 (Box 26)
  - Virginia Psychological Association Constitution 1962 (Box 26)
  - Virginia Psychological Association Examination Board 1972-1973 (Box 27)
  - Virginia Psychological Foundation 1984-1990 (Box 27)
  - Virginia Academy of Academic Psychologists and Virginia Psychological Association 1983-1989 (Box 27)
  - Virginia Psychological Association Board of Directors 1979-1983 (Box 27)
  - Visual Aids for American Psychological Association Division I: Presidential Address 1961 (Box 27)
  - Weldon Case 1968-1972 (Box 27)
- VI: Foreign Travel
  - Austria and Hungary 1987-1992, 2 folders (Box 27)
  - Brazil (Brasil) 1988 (Box 27)
  - Brazil 1988-1992 (Box 28)
  - China and Japan 1984-1985 (Box 28)
  - Costa Rica 1995 (Box 28)
  - Costa Rica, England, Wales, Ireland 1995 (Box 28)
  - England 1975-1976 (Box 28)
  - England and New Zealand 1975-1981 (Box 28)
  - Foreign Travel 1988-1995 (Box 28)
  - France 1983-1984, 2 folders (Box 29)
  - Germany 1987 (Box 29)
  - Great Britain 1995 (Box 29)
  - India 1984-1991, 2 folders (Box 29)
  - India--Elderhostel India Programs 1987 (Box 29)
  - Indonesia 1993 (Box 29)
  - Ireland, Orient 1983-1985 (Box 29)
  - Israel 1988 (Box 30)
  - Israel, Egypt, Greece, and Turkey 1988, 2 folders (Box 30)
  - Kenya, Scandinavia, Java 1989-1993 (Box 30)
  - Kenya 1975-1994 (Box 30)
  - Lectures in New Zealand 1981 (Box 30)
  - Leningrad Meeting 1969-1971 (Box 30)
  - New Zealand 1981 (Box 30)
  - New Zealand 1981 (Box 30)
  - Other Countries 1977 (Box 30)
  - Scandinavia 1992-1993 (Box 30)
- VII: General Files
  - Aging Conference 1974 (Box 30)
  - Algernon Sydney Sullivan Award 1977-1984 (Box 30)
  - Annual Review 1967-1992 (Box 31)
  - Annual Review Chapter 1971 (Box 31)
  - Avery 1974-1979 (Box 31)
  - Batson, John 1979 (Box 31)
  - Brown 1971-1979 (Box 31)
  - Brown, Steve 1974 (Box 31)
  - Brown--ICI Short Course (Identification and Criticism of Ideas) 1954-1955 (Box 31)
  - Buxton--The Teaching of Psychology in College 1953-1954 (Box 31)
  - Carbon of Chapter Final Draft 1970-1971 (Box 31)
  - Career Development 1971-1972 (Box 31)
  - The Cavalier Daily 1975 (Box 31)
  - Finger's Cemetery Committee 1955-1980 (Box 31)
    see Box 46
  - Cemetery Committee 1982-1990 (Box 31)
  - Cemetery Committee 1986-1990, 2 folders (Box 32)
  - Cemetery History 1915-1988 (Box 32)
  - Chair Research Support 1971-1985 (Box 32)
  - Chapel Committee 1956-1989, 3 folders (Box 32)
  - Chapel Committee--Minutes of Communication 1975-1979, 2 folders (Box 32)
  - History of University Chapel 1980 (Box 32)
  - Chapter--Journal Searched 1967-1969 (Box 33)
  - Clippings 1980-1987, 2 folders (Box 33)
  - College Committee on Report of Faculty Student Committee 1949 (Box 33)
  - College Constitution (Rejected) 1954 (Box 33)
  - College Faculty Meetings 1944-1953, 3 folders (Box 33)
  - Committee Business 1976-1977 (Box 33)
  - Committee on Educational Program and Organization 1964 (Box 33)
  - Committee Structure 1962 (Box 33)
  - Combined Degree Committee 1947-1950 (Box 33)
  - Congressional Record 1979 (Box 33)
  - Course on the "College Teacher" 1952-1955 (Box 33)
  - Courses in Canterbury 1981 (Box 33)
  - Current Problems Activity 1965 (Box 34)
  - Curricular Plans Here and There--Yale 1952-1955 (Box 34)
  - Data--Arts and Sciences Faculty 1959-1963 (Box 34)
  - Debts 1971 (Box 34)
  - Psychology Department 1975 (Box 34)
  - Psychology Department Finances 1928-1946 (Box 34)
  - Department Finances 1942 (Box 34)
  - Department of the Army 1979 (Box 34)
  - Departmental Self Analysis 1954 (Box 34)
  - Mary Diche 1977 (Box 34)
  - Division I Presidential Address 1961 (Box 34)
  - Division III Presidential Address 1972, 2 folders (Box 34)
  - Draft 1967-1969 (Box 34)
  - Educational/Institutional Policies and Practices 1980 (Box 34)
  - Emory 1959 (Box 34)
  - Eustis 1975-1977 (Box 34)
  - Examining Board 1966-1970, 2 folders (Box 35)
  - Faculty Committee on Athletic Situation 1953 (Box 35)
  - Faculty Self-Study 1960-1964, 4 folders (Box 35)
  - Final Grant Report 1978 (Box 35)
  - Finger's Thesis on Conforming Behavior in Greeting of Women by Men 1936-1937 (Box 35)
  - Dr. Frank Finger 1963 (Box 35)
  - Finger's Work 1976-1977 (Box 35)
  - Formal Talks 1964-1986, 2 folders (Box 36)
  - Fraternity Committee 1955-1958 (Box 36)
  - Gallup Poll 1939 (Box 36)
  - Gooch Athletic Report 1951 (Box 36)
  - A "Good" Lecture 1966 (Box 36)
  - Graduate Work 1959-1967 (Box 36)
  - Greensboro, State University of New York, Tulane, Louisiana State University Graduate Programs 1969-1977 (Box 36)
  - High School 1959-1978 (Box 36)
  - Higher Education 1974-1975 (Box 36)
  - History Terminology 1968-1983, 2 folders (Box 37)
  - Honor Committee 1979-1985, 2 folders (Box 37)
  - Honor Committee--Clippings 1984-1985 (Box 37)
  - Hopkins Colloquium 1951 (Box 37)
  - Ideas for Report 1963 (Box 37)
  - Igel 1966-1979 (Box 37)
  - Individualized Science Instructional System 1973 (Box 37)
  - Innovation in Curricula 1953-1971 (Box 37)
  - Insanity Plea 1983 (Box 37)
  - The International Encyclopedia of Higher Education 1977 (Box 37)
  - International Society for Chronobiology 1979-1995 (Box 37)
  - International Society of Chronobiology Meeting 1979 (Box 37)
  - Interviews 1963 (Box 38)
  - Jobs in Psychology 1963-1980, 2 folders (Box 38)
  - Leave of Absence 1981 (Box 38)
  - Little Rock Meeting 1971 (Box 38)
  - Louisville 1967 (Box 38)
  - Mary Washington College 1979 (Box 38)
  - Material on Chautauqua--type short courses (Rhythm) 1978-1980 (Box 38)
  - Mathematics and Science Center Session 1983 (Box 38)
  - Mathematics and Science Center Session--High School Group 1983 (Box 38)
  - McGill University 1972 (Box 38)
  - Mental Health Law Project File 1977 (Box 38)
  - Michigan Teaching Conference 1972 (Box 38)
  - Motivation and Drive of Psychologists 1959-1964 (Box 38)
  - NATO Conference--Hanover 1979 (Box 38)
  - Note Cards 1975-1981 (Box 39)
  - Notes 1971 (Box 39)
  - The Numbers Game 1971-1978 (Box 39)
  - Organization of Departments 1965 (Box 39)
  - Personnel Mental Facilities Clippings 1965-1966 (Box 39)
  - PH.D Thesis: Quantitative Study of "Conflict" 1940 (Box 39)
  - Philip Morris 1970 (Box 39)
  - Physical Education College Committee 1952 (Box 39)
  - Policy Documents and Reports of the American Association of University Professors 1969 (Box 39)
  - Political Campaigns 1964 (Box 39)
  - Preliminary Report to the President from the President's Commission on Mental Health 1977 (Box 39)
  - Preparation of Proposals for Research and Building Support 1964-1965 (Box 39)
  - Preparation of Teachers 1955-1971 (Box 39)
  - Printed--Articles, Booklets 1977-1982 (Box 39)
  - Problem Athletes 1983 (Box 39)
  - Processions Committee 1948-1949 (Box 40)
  - Project to Improve College Teaching 1970 (Box 40)
  - Programs in Other Sciences Curricula 1968-1970 (Box 40)
  - Psychological Research Facilities 1963, 3 folders (Box 40)
  - Psychological Research Facilities at Fordham University 1963 (Box 40)
  - Psychology Employment Status 1969-1976 (Box 40)
  - Psychology Major Programs 1968 (Box 40)
  - Ravenna Meeting 1974 (Box 40)
  - Reading Rates on Higher Education 1946-1968 (Box 40)
  - Recommendations 1944-1991, 3 folders (Box 40)
  - Records 1961-1963 (Box 40)
  - Report 1963-1964 (Box 41)
  - Reprints Needing Presentation 1880-1889 (Box 41)